Lothar Wolff collection, 1926-1987
George Eastman Museum
- Series 5, Publications/Clippings, 1932-1946; 1951-1984
  - no title (Box C356)
    - [Album labeled "Denmark 1934/36 and 1939"], 1934-1940; 1982 (Folder 7)
      Clippings, including Danish newspaper articles regarding filming of Flugten fra Millionerne and Fredløs; U.S. newspaper clippings regarding Nazis; 2/14/1982 New York Times Book Review of The Kennedy Imprisonment by Garry Wills.
  - no title (Box C367)
    - Two Issues of Mein Film, ca. 1932 (Folder 4)
      Two undated issues of German film magazine [in German].
    - Published Photographs by Lothar Wolff, 1939-1946 (Folder 7)
      Time,Ken, and Survey Graphic magazine articles featuring photographs credited to Wolff.
    - Flugten fra Millionerne( 1934 ) Dk. D. Paul Fejos Newspaper Clippings & Photographs, 1933-1935 (Folder 20)
      Clipping from Danish Social-Demokraten newspaper re: Fejos and Flugten fra Millionerne[in Danish].
    - Newspaper Clippings for Frühlingsstimmen& Other Films by Fejos, ca. 1932 (Folder 21)
    - Newspaper Clippings on Several Films & Rochemont, 1933; 1956-1962; 1966 (Folder 27)
      Clippings about Question 7, Cinerama, Nazi film, Wolff’s career.
    - Louis de Rochemont Obituary, 1978 (Folder 28)
      December 27, 1978 Variety obituary; December 25, 1978 letter to the managing editor of the New York Times correcting the obituary's attribution of the production of Martin Luther to de Rochemont.
    - Articles on Natural Science, 1957; 1974; 1979-1982 (Folder 29a)
      Magazine articles, newspaper clippings, booklets, reports, and notes in Wolff’s hand regarding astronomy, ancient history, geological surveyor Richard S. Williams Jr..
    - Articles on Natural Science, 1957; 1979-1981 (Folder 29b)
      Newspaper clippings, magazine articles, publications regarding the environment, physics, astronomy, geology, earth sciences, archeology; 1979 NASA Films catalog.
    - Articles on Natural Science, 1973-1982 (Folder 29c)
      Newspaper clippings, booklets, reports, and papers regarding earth sciences, astronomy; satellite-image maps of Iceland.
    - U.S. Industrial Film Festival Joy of Bach-- Gold Camera Award, 1982 (Folder 33)
      Also contains two 1982 Variety columns regarding Animal Farm.
  - no title (Box C368)
    - [Newspaper Clippings, 1951-1966 ] (Folder 16)
  - no title (Box OS-1)
    - [Ballooning artwork and clippings], ca. 1984 (Folder 2)
      1980 Archaeology magazine article about ballooning; several pages removed from the book The Aeronauts(see Box C313, Folder 56).
    - [Country Life magazine, 1983 (Folder 13)
- Series 6, Personal Records, 1926-1940; 1946; 1968-1972; 1984-1985; undated
  Series contains documents of a personal nature, unrelated to Wolff's filmmaking or other business activities. Materials include correspondence, including cards and letters from Louise Brooks; medical records; an interview transcript; and receipts.
  Series materials are located in three boxes. When discernible, arrangement is in reverse chronological order.
  - no title (Box C301)
    - Glenda Jackson, Nederlander Theatre, 1985 (Folder 52)
      Postcard from Jackson, letter [photocopy] from Wolff to Jackson.
  - no title (Box C309)
    - [Three-ring loose-leaf binder labeled "March of Time I"], 1933-1948; 1979 (Folder 20)
      Paul Fejos's telegram to Wolff's mother; photographs of Wolff; cartoons celebrating Wolff's U.S. citizenship.
    - [Three-ring loose-leaf binder labeled "March of Time II"], 1936; 1940-1943 (Folder 21)
      Photographs of Wolff;J. Edgar Hoover portrait (signed); correspondence regarding Wolff's enlistment in the U.S. Coast Guard; materials congratulating Wolff on his U.S. citizenship.
  - no title (Box C314)
    - Time, Inc. Medical Department reports for Lothar Wolff, 1968-1972 (Folder 38)
      Medical examination reports.
  - no title (Box C356)
    - [Postcards album],,], 1928-1931; 1936 (Folder 8)
      Postcards and snapshots featuring Arnold Höllriegel,Annabella,Camilla Horn,Truus van Aalten,Karl Freund;Karel Lamač,Anny Ondra, and Wolff in a carnival cutout; topographical postcards featuring views of Lisbon, Paris, Verdun, Windsor Castle; opening ceremony of the 1936 Olympics in Berlin from "Paul" (possibly Fejos); cartoon sketch "Avant -- Apres." Captions and correspondence is in German, French, and English.
    - [Album labeled "3. Budapest -- Vienna -- Cruise 12/33-1/34 "], 1932-1933 (Folder 6)
      Letter of confirmation dated 3/22/1933 for Wolff's employment in Vienna as assistant director/editor in "'Fejos'-Film." In German.
  - no title (Box C367)
    - : Old Contracts and Evaluations for Lothar Wolff, 1926-1933 (Folder 5)
      Wolff’s school evaluation from Rackow’s Kaufmännischen Privatschule [in German]; contracts and correspondence regarding Wolff’s employment with Parufamet,Hom Films,Ondra-Lamac-Film, and Ernst Wolf Film.
    - Lothar Wolff -- Dates/Work, undated (Folder 6)
      Curriculum vitae
    - Announcement of Christmas Check from Time-Life, 1936 (Folder 8)
      Congratulatory telegram to Wolff from "Morris and Adele" dated 3/12/1936; Letter regarding Wolff’s Time, Inc. Christmas bonus dated 12/19/1936.
    - Aufenthaltsbescheinigung for Lothar Wolff, 5. Juni, 1940 (Folder 9)
      German residence certificate dated 6/5/1940. In German.
    - Treasury Silver Medal Award for L.W. March 12, 1946 (Folder 10)
      Letter from US Treasury Department announcing the presentation of the Silver Medal Award to Wolff.
    - Lothar Wolff: Movie Work in Europe 1931-35, undated (Folder 11)
      List of countries and number of months Wolff spent in each working as editor and/or assistant director.
    - LW/ Professional Background, ca. 1969; 1972 (Folder 12)
      Curricula vitae/resumes and photocopies of employment documents from Parufamet and Hom Films; 1972 issue of Ohio State University’s Journal of the University Film Association containing Wolff’s speech "Reminiscences of an Itinerant Filmmaker".
    - Interview with Lothar Wolff, 1985 (Folder 13)
      Steno service transcript of taped interview with corrections in Wolff’s hand.
    - Bills from Trip to Indonesia & Japan, 1984 (Folder 19)
      Receipts and travel agent’s information relating to Wolff’s trip to Indonesia, Japan, and Hawaii.
    - 1958 (IGY), undated (Folder 40)
      Pen on paper cartoon featuring caricature of Wolff.
    - [Louise Brooks], 1977-1986; undated (Folder 41)
      Greeting cards, notes and other correspondence to Wolff from Brooks; newspaper and magazine clippings, several by biographer Barry Paris; Barry Paris résumé; correspondence to Wolff from Barry Paris regarding Brooks,G.W. Pabst; 8" x 10" black-and-white publicity photograph of Louise Brooks; "Ein weing Louise Brooks" magazine article by Louise Brooks [in German]; undated Great Lakes Theatre program featuring A Girl in Every Port; documents related to BBC-TV's Arena segment on Brooks; photocopies of reverse side (with captions) of 8" x 10" still photographs from The Bad Man and Those Who Dance.
- Series 7, Photographs, 1927-1984; undated
  This series consists of 35 albums and folders, covering the span of Lothar Wolff’s career, with a date range of 1927-1984. Some materials are undated. Subjects include Wolff’s time in Prague, as well as the production of many films with which Wolff was involved, such as Martin Luther( 1953 ),The Roman Spring of Mrs. Stone( 1961 ), and The Sky’s the Limit( 1983 ). In addition, this series covers many of the film festivals Wolff attended; his work helping to construct a film lab in Indonesia in 1950s; and The March of Time retrospective tour in the 1980s, and other events. Notable among the persons featured in the photographs are Louise Brooks, Anny Ondra, Fritz Lang,Oskar Werner, Vivien Leigh, Warren Beatty, Jill St. John, Pablo Casals, and Louis de Rochemont. The series also includes signed photographs of Anna May Wong,Truus van Aalten, and G.W. Pabst, among others. In addition to photographic prints, the albums include negatives, newspaper clippings, pamphlets, correspondence, and music scores, each related to the subject of the album.
  During processing the original order of the albums, including the placement of such non-photographic materials as clippings and correspondence, was maintained.
  - no title (Box C300)
    - [Binder labeled "Parade of Witnesses," Oct./Nov. 83], 1983 (Folder 1)
    - [Photo album labeled "Rome, 1961"],"] (Folder 2)
    - [Album labeled "Puerto Rico Fortaleza, Feb. 57"], 1957-1958 (Folder 3)
    - [Unlabeled Question 7 photo album], ca. 1961; 1969 (Folder 4)
    - [Photo album labeled " 79/84 misc."], 1979-1984 (Folder 5)
      Photos taken during the March of Time retrospectives in Berlin (1979) and Tokyo (1984); at the University of Mexico, featuring astronomer Clyde Tombaugh, cameraman Jim Carr; in London with producer Helen Brew; Munich, with Heinrich Krauss; Sydney, Australia; Belmont, MA. Also includes photos of Wolff receiving an honorary degree at Thiel College in 1983.
    - [Binder labeled " 79 Yorkton & Florence Film Festivals"], 1979 (Folder 6)
    - [Photo album labeled " 1983 The Sky’s the Limit France & US"] (Folder 7)
    - [Album labeled "Indonesia 53/55 "], 1953-1955 (Folder 8)
      Black-and-white photos taken during Wolff's tenure in Indonesia. Album pages are dated from 1953 through 1955. Subjects include Lothar and Violet Wolff; the Perussahann Film Negara company; U.S. Ambassador to Indonesia Hugh Cumming.
    - [Photo album labeled "Switzerland 63/64"], 1963-1964 (Folder 9)
    - [Photo album originally labeled "DI 63/64"], 1963-1964 (Folder 10)
  - no title (Box C301)
    - Stewart Halperin, 1980-1982 (Folder 22)
      Slide sheet of 12 35mm transparencies taken by US photographer Stewart Halperin featuring Swiss artist Theo Meier in his Thailand studio.
    - Prof. Dr.Thomas Koebner--Philipps-Universität Marburg concerning the publication of History of Filmemigration, 1981-1984 (Folder 60)
      Two black-and-white group photographs featuring Wolff as a young man.
  - no title (Box C308)
    - Joy of Bach, ca. 1979 (Folder 9)
      Photograph contact sheets for The Joy of Bach including production, location shots; landscape with tracing paper; 2 8x10 black-and-white negatives for radio station KFAC's "Bachanalia" ad; 8x10 black-and-white photo of Robert Deutsch,Rosalyn Tureck and the Moog synthesizer.
    - Manfred Schnelle( 1978 ) DDR Choreog. (Folder 10)
    - St. Thomas Kirche Leipzig, 1977 (Folder 11)
      Two black-and-white photographs of the gate at St. Thomas Church.
    - Joy of Bach DDR -- Location, 1978 (Folder 12)
    - [Binder labeled "The Joy of Bach 77/78 Vol. 1 12" on spine], 1977-1978 (Folder 24)
    - [Binder labeled "The Joy of Bach’78 Vol. 2 13"], 1978 (Folder 25)
    - [Binder labeled "The Joy of Bach Vol. 3 14"], ca. 1978 (Folder 26)
  - no title (Box C309)
    - Photos taken during March of Time filming, 1938; 1941; undated (Folder 3)
      Some photos dated 1938 and 1941. Mostly undated.
    - [Three-ring loose-leaf binder labeled "March of Time I"], 1933-1948; 1979 (Folder 20)
      Photographs of Wolff and March of Time personnel.
    - [Three-ring loose-leaf binder labeled "March of Time II"], 1936; 1940-1943 (Folder 21)
      Photographs of Wolff, Louis de Rochemont,March of Time production Norway in Revolt;J. Edgar Hoover portrait (signed).
  - no title (Box C313)
    - The Sky’s the Limit-- The Balloon Intercomparison Campaign -- Palestine, Texas, April, 1983 (Folder 13)
    - Ballooning --The Sky's the Limit Photographs, 1969; 1971; 1983 (Folder 46)
  - no title (Box C355)
    - Sun -- Photographs, 1974-1977 (Folder 38)
      Black-and-white 8 x 10 photographs of the sun, sunspots.
    - Photographs, undated (Folder 39)
      Black-and-white photographs of book plate featuring Cheseaux’s Comet with a transparent paper shot overlay;Jules Verne’s moon train and great cannon; composite lunar eclipses. Color photographs of the moon.
    - Voyager Photos, 1979 (Folder 40)
      Color photographs of Jupiter and its moons taken by Voyagers 1 and 2.
  - no title (Box C356)
    - [Photo album, "Zur Erinnerung an den Film Martin Luther Mr. Lothar Wolff herzlichst gewidmet, Wiesbaden August-October 1952"] (Folder 1)
      ["Commemorating the film Martin Luther, Mr. Lothar Wolff, sincerely dedicated, Wiesbaden August-October 1952] Commemorative album of black-and-white photographs taken during the production of Martin Luther. Title page in German. Album is likely the first of a three-volume commemorative set. See Box C356, Folders 2 and 3.
    - [Album labeled "Martin Luther Vol. II, 1952"], 1953 (Folder 2)
    - [Album labeled "Martin Luther Vol. III 1952"] (Folder 3)
    - [Album labeled "1. Berlin Prag 1927/31"], 1926-1931; 1979-1984 (Folder 4)
      Contains photographs dating from Wolff's tenure as press agent and/or film editor in Berlin and Prague. Includes snapshots and portraits taken during the production of G.W. Pabst's Diary of a Lost Girl(1929) and Westfront 1918(1930); the Hom-AG productions Der Ruf des Nordens(1929) and Die heiligen drei Brunnen(1930); and the Ondra-Lamač Film productions Die Vom Rummelplatz/Fair People(1930),Eine Freundin So Goldig Wei Du(1930),Er Und Seine Schwester/Meet the Sister(1931), and Der Zinker/The Squeeker(1931). Photos are arranged according to production and are chronologically ordered. Several appear to have been removed from the album. Notable subjects are Wolff; Louise Brooks and sister June Brooks;G.W. Pabst;Fritz Lang with Carl Laemmle and Erich Pommer; and Karel Lamač with Robert Flaherty. Signed portraits include Anna May Wong(shot by Eugene Robert Richee on the set of Paramount's Forty Winks, released in Germany -- most likely by Parfumet -- in 1926 as Heiraten ist kein Kinderspiel); Pabst;Truss van Aalten; and Anny Ondra. Also contains clippings from Film Kurier ca. 1930; an Er Und Seine Schwester/Meet the Sister press book; a 8/7/1979 New York Times clipping about Brooks visiting George Eastman House; a 6/15/1982 Variety review of Lulu in Hollywood by "Ever." (possibly William K. Everson); photos of Hans Casparius in London, 1983; and a 5/1984 Films in Review article about Luis Trenker by Everson. Materials are in English and German.
    - [Album labeled "2.Mamsell Nitouche--Monsieur le Maréchal--Baroud--Poliche 1931/34"], 1931-1934; 1980-1981 (Folder 5)
      Black-and-white snapshots taken during the productions of Mamsell Nitouche,Baroud,Monsieur le Maréchal,Sergeant X, and Poliche; photographs of Anny Ondra, Alice Terry [signed], Rosita Garcia [signed], Roland Caillaux [signed], and Abel Gance with Louis-Ferdinand Celine;Rex Ingram. Also includes materials related to Francis Ford Coppola's 1980 presentation of Abel Gance’s Napoleon, and clipping from Film Directions Issue 8. In French and English.
    - [Album labeled "3. Budapest -- Vienna -- Cruise 12/33-1/34 "], 1932-1933 (Folder 6)
      Photographs taken during the production of Roi de Palace/King of Hotels in Budapest, May-December 1932, featuring Wolff,Betty Stockfeld(signed),Jules Berry(signed),Armand Dranem,Simone Simon(signed);Sonnenstrahl/Ray of Sunshine in Vienna 1933, featuring Wolff,Paul Fejos,Annabella,René Sti; and Frühlingsstimmen in Bad Ischl and Semmering, Austria, featuring Wolff, Fejos,Adele Kern,Ursula Grabley,Szöke Szakall. Invitation to the Frühlingsstimmen world premiere. Photos of Wachau, Salzburg, Castle Kreutzenstein, Diana-Bad, Bratislava. Materials in German.
    - [Album labeled "Denmark 1934/36 and 1939"], 1934-1940; 1982 (Folder 7)
      Though not numbered, this is likely the fourth in the series of photo albums preceded by albums in Box C356, Folders 1, 2, and 3. Contains photographs taken during the production of Flugten fra Millionerne/Millions in Flight in Copenhagen and Norway, July 1934, featuring Paul Fejos,Inga Arvad,Louis Larsen(also in 35mm film strip), and Erling Schroeder(signed portrait);Fange No. 1;Det Gyldne Smil/The Golden Smile, March 1935, featuring Fejos,Bodil Ipsen,Carl Alstrup;Fredløs, Fall 1935, featuring Gull-Maj Norin,Sten Lindgren,John Ekman. Photos also feature Nordisk Film Studios, Valby; Copenhagen residence on Herman Triers Pl.; Copenhagen street scenes dated 9/4/1939, including the Danish Nazi party headquarters; "Shooting for The March of Time"; Danish prime minister Thorvald Stauning. Album also contains letter from Copenhagen Chief of State Police regarding Nordisk; signed portrait of composer Ferenc Farkas and Farkas sheet music inscribed to Wolff. Materials are in Danish, German, and English.
    - [Postcards album],,], 1928-1931; 1936 (Folder 8)
    - Misc. Photographs, 1947; 1967; 1974; undated (Folder 9)
      Group photograph of Wolff, Violet Wolff, and MoMA's Margareta Akermark at dinner during the 1967 Philadelphia Film Festival; front and back of a 1947 Festival Mondial du Film et des Beaux-Arts de Belgique plaque recognizing Storm over Britain; "M. Monaco" receiving an award from the Office Catholique International du Cinema; color photographs of galaxy, Galileo's telescope. A page of small black-and-white photographs taken in Rome during location shooting for The Roman Spring of Mrs. Stone was originally located in this folder but was moved to the "Rome, 1961" album located in Box C300 during processing by Ken Fox on 7/13/2015.
  - no title (Box C367)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs, 1930-1960; 1971-1972; ca. 1983; undated (Folder 14)
      Subjects include G.W. Pabst on the set of Westfront 1918(undated);Man Ray(1934); Grand Canal, Venice, and Florence (erroneously captioned Venice), 1933; Wolff and others aboard the SS. Scanmail (1/1936); de Rochemont Christmas cards; Wolff with Bill Colleran,Borden Mace, and Thomas Orchard(Louis de Rochemont Associates), 1956; Wolff at an LLM dinner, 1960; Wolff at 1971 Time-Life Films Christmas party; undated contact sheets; headshots of Wolff; Wolff and Lutheran Film Associates president Paul C. Empie signing a Question 7 production contract, undated; Wolff and Robert E. A. Lee at a 1972 ceremony commemorating Question 7; Wolff receiving a CINE 1969 award for the "Survival in the Sea" episode of The World We Live In; color photo of Wolff film a balloon for Sky's the Limit.
    - Flugten fra Millionerne( 1934 ) Dk. D. Paul Fejos Newspaper Clippings & Photographs, 1933-1935 (Folder 20)
      Black-and-white photographs featuring Paul Fejos, actors, and crew during production of Fange nr. 1,Frühlingsstimmen, and others.
  - no title (Box C368)
    - [Newspaper Clippings, 1951-1966] (Folder 16)
      Photographs related to "A Living Church,"Question 7,Parlons Français.
    - Question 7, ca. 1961 (Folder 19)
  - no title (Box OS-2)
    - [Envelope labeled "Lothar Wolf Prod. – Artwork of ‘Voyage through Space’ – Cataloged 4-28-87 UA"], 1964; 1979-1980; 1987 (Folder 6)
      Postcard of Kitt Peak National Observatory; photographic reproductions of an 18th-century text about a 1644 comet with illustrations and transparent paper overlays indicating camera instructions; subfolders containing photographs and negatives of planets and engravings of observatories, solar orbits (glued to acetate sheets), astronomical instruments, astrological symbolism, and fantasies of interplanetary travel and extraterrestrial life; large photo of Pablo Casals conducting, with note from Ken Sales on reverse. Materials were removed from original envelope and foldered August, 2015.
- Series 8, Film/Video, 1943-1953; 1960-1961; 1966-1986; undated
  The majority of the films in this collection were produced as episodes of several film series, most for television broadcast. "Series 8, Film/Video" is divided into eight subseries according to film series title. Films not part of a film series, including feature films, comprise "Subseries 9, Features and Other Non-series Films."
  Films and videotapes have been transferred to the safety vaults of the Moving Image Department at the George Eastman Museum. For inquiries regarding access to these materials, please contact the Film Study Center at filmstudycenter@eastman.org.
  - Subseries 1, Coast Guard Films, 1944; undated
    - LST -- Landing Ship Tanks, undated
      16mm print
      Accession no.: 1989:1324:0001
    - Normandy Invasion, 1944
      Two 16mm prints. Print 1989:1456:0001 is currently housed in the "Vinegar Room."
      Accession No.: 1975:0007:1780
      Accession No.: 1989:1456:0001
    - U.S. Coast Guard Report #7, undated
      Accession No.: 1989:1349:0001
  - Subseries 2,The Earth and Its Peoples, 1948-1949
    - Farmers of India -- The Ganges Valley, 1949
      Accession No.: 1989:1321:0001
    - Nomads of the Jungle, 1948
      Accession No.: 1989:1326:0001
  - Subseries 3,The March of Time, 1943; 1947
    - End of an Empire?, 1947
      Accession No.: 1987:1498:0001 (Possible deaccession)
    - One Day of War -- Russia 1943
      Accession No.: 1989:1323:0001
    - Storm over Britain, 1947
      Accession No.: 1989:1325:0001
  - Subseries 4,Other People, Other Places, 1974
    - Ghosts at the End of the Earth, ca. 1974
      Accession No.: 1989:1458:0001
  - Subseries 5,Planet Earth, 1960-1961
    - Challenge of the Oceans, 1961
      Accession No.: 1989:1380:0001
    - Cosmic Rays, 1960
      Accession No.: 1989:1375:0001
    - Flaming Sky, 1960
      Accession No.: 1989:1454:0001
    - The Force of Gravity, 1960
      Two 16mm prints
      Accession No.: 1989:1370:0001
      Accession No.: 1989:1371:0001
    - The Hidden Earth, 1960
      Accession No.: 1989:1381:0001
    - The Inconstant Air, 1960
      Accession No.: 1989:1366:0001
      Accession No.: 1989:1367:0001
    - Magnetic Force, 1960
      Accession No.: 1989:1368:0001
      Accession No.: 1989:1369:0001
    - The Nearest Star[aka The Nearest Star: Sun and Solar Activity], 1960
      Two 16mm prints, one entered into The Museum System as The Nearest Star: Sun and Solar Activity.
      Accession No. (The Nearest Star: Sun and Solar Activity): 1989:1372:0001
      Accession No. (The Nearest Star: Sun and Solar Activity): 1989:1373:0001
    - Radio Waves, 1960
      Accession No.: 1989:1378:0001
      Accession No.: 1989:1379:0001
    - Research by Rockets, 1960
      Accession No.: 1989:1377:0001
    - Science in Space, 1960
      Accession No.: 1989:1376:0001
    - Secrets of the Ice, 1960
      Accession No.: 1989:1374:0001
    - The Shape of the Earth, 1960
      Accession No.: 1989:1364:0001
      Accession No.: 1989:1365:0001
  - Subseries 6,The Sun and the Earth, ca. 1966
    - The Active Sun, ca. 1966
      Three 16mm prints.
      Accession No.: 1989:1358:0001
      Accession No.: 1989:1359:0001
      Accession No.: 1989:1360:0001
    - Interplanetary Space, ca. 1966
      Accession No.: 1989:1355:0001
    - The Magnetosphere, ca. 1966
      Accession No.: 1989:1354:0001
    - The Quiet Sun, ca. 1966
      Accession No.: 1989:1356:0001
      Accession No.: 1989:1357:0001
  - Subseries 7,Wild, Wild World of Animals, ca. 1973
    - Monkeys of Koshima, ca. 1973
      Accession No.: 1989:1352:0001
    - Swans, The Royal Birds, ca. 1973
      Accession No.: 1989:1353:0001
    - Tropical Web of Life, ca. 1973
      Accession No.: 1989:1455:0001
  - Subseries 8,The World We Live In, 1968-1973
    - After the Whale, ca. 1970
      Accession No.: 1989:1385:0001
    - Antarctica, Because It's There, 1968
      16mm print.
      Accession No.: 1989:1384:0001
    - The Dam Builders, 1968
      Accession No.: 1989:1383:0001
    - How Old Is Old?, 1970
      Accession No.: 1989:1386:0001
      Accession No.: 1989:1387:0001
    - Question of Time, 1973
      Accession No.: 1989:1382:0001
    - Riddle of Heredity, 1968
      Accession No.: 1989:1390:0001
    - Rock-a-Bye Baby, ca. 1971
      Accession No.: 1989:1394:0001
    - Small Wilderness, 1970
      Accession No.: 1989:1331:0001
    - The Sun Watchers, 1968
      Accession No.: 1989:1392:0001